Leslie Stephen Photograph Album, 1856-1894
Mortimer Rare Book Room, William Allan Neilson Library, Smith College
Leslie Stephen Photograph Album
1856-1894
Stephen, Leslie, 1832-1904, compiler
MS 5
3 boxes, oversize (1 linear ft.)
Mortimer Rare Book Room Smith College Northampton, MA
English literary critic, author, man of letters, father of Virginia Woolf and Vanessa Bell, and first editor of the Dictionary of National Biography. Contains 73 photographs taken between 1856 and 1894 and mounted on 16 leaves.
Biographical Note
Son of Jane Catherine Venn and Sir James Stephen. He was born November 28, 1832, in London, and he died February 22, 1904, in London.
English critic, man of letters, and first editor of the Dictionary of National Biography.
A member of a distinguished intellectual family, Stephen was educated at Eton, at King's College, London and at Trinity Hall, Cambridge, where he was elected to a fellowship in 1854 and became junior tutor in 1856. He was ordained in 1859, but his philosophical studies, combined probably with the controversy that followed the publication of Charles Darwin's Origin of Species (1859), caused him to loose his faith; in 1862 he resigned his tutorship and two years later left Cambridge to live in London.
Through his brother, James Fitzjames Stephen, a contributor to the Saturday Review, Stephen gained entry to the literary world, contributing to many periodicals. In 1871 George Smith offered him the editorship of The Cornhill Magazine, for which he wrote literary criticism later republished in the three series of Hours in a Library (1874-1879). Stephen was one of the first serious critics of the novel, and his works still deserves considerations by the historians of literary criticism. Thomas Hardy, Robert Louis Stevenson, Edmund Gosse, and Henry James were among those whom Stephen, as an editor, encouraged. After eleven years he resigned from the editorship of Cornhill, but he continued to write for periodicals.
His greatest learned work was his History of English Thought in the Eighteenth Century (1876). His philosophical study The English Utilitarians (1900) was somewhat less successful, though it is still a useful source. His philosophical contribution to the rationalist tradition, Science of Ethics (1882), attempted to wed evolutionary theory to ethics. Stephen's most enduring legacy, however, is the Dictionary of National Biography, which he edited from 1882 to 1891. He edited the first 26 volumes and contributed 378 biographies to that important reference work. In recognition of this service to letters he was created Knight Commander of the Bath in 1902 and received other honours. Stephen's English Literature and Society in the Eighteen Century (1904) was a pioneer work in the sociological study of literature.
Stephen was shy and given to silence, the more so after the death in 1875 of his first wife, Harriet Marian, the second daughter of William Makepeace Thackeray. In 1878 he married Julia Jackson, the widow of Herbert Duckworth, and among their four children were painter Vanessa Bell and the novelist Virginia Woolf. Noel G. Annan's Leslie Stephen: His Thought and Character in Relation to His Time (1952; reprinted, Walter P. Metzger, ed., 1977) is a notable study. Sir Leslie Stephen's Mausoleum Book (1978), edited by Alan Bell, is an autobiography written after the death of Stephen's wife Julia in 1895.
From "Stephen, Sir Leslie." Encyclopædia Britannica. 2003.
Encyclopædia Britannica Online. 30 May, 2003
Scope and Contents of the Collection
Compiled circa 1895. 39 leaves; 57 x 46 cm. Leaves 1-15, 18-23, 26-27 and leather covers are lacking.
This photograph album currently contains 73 photographs taken between 1856 and 1894 and mounted on 16 leaves by Leslie Stephen in 1895. The photographs document the family of British author and editor Leslie Stephen (1832-1904), including his first marriage to Harriet Marian Thackeray Stephen (1840-1875) and their daughter Laura Makepeace Stephen (1870-1945). In addition, the album contains early images of Julia Prinsep Jackson, her family, and her first marriage to Herbert Duckworth (1833-1870), including their children George Duckworth (1868-1934), Stella Duckworth (1869-1897), and Gerald Duckworth (1870-1937). The final four leaves document the marriage of Julia Duckworth Stephen (1846-1895) to Leslie Stephen. They also contain early photographs of their children, including Vanessa Bell (1879-1961), Thoby Stephen (1880-1906), Virginia Woolf (1882-1941), and Adrian Stephen (1883-1948). There are also photographs of friends of the family including James Russell Lowell (1819-1891) and Henry James (1843-1916). The album records Victorian fashion, including mourning customs and outdoor activities such as hiking and fishing.
There are a few prints by famous photographers, including Julia Margaret Cameron (1815-1879), Henry Herschel Hay Cameron (1852-1911), Camille Silvy (1834-1910), Gabriel Loppé, Oscar G. Rejlander (1813-1875), and Lock & Whitfield. Most prints, however, are anonymous. A variety of photographic techniques are represented, including albumen, platinum, and silver prints. Many are undated. Most of the photographs were taken in England (Cornwall, London, Somerset, Sussex), but a few, mounted on the final leaf, were taken at Alpine resorts in Switzerland.
The album was compiled by Leslie Stephen after Julia Stephen's death on 5 May 1895. The list of contents, leaf numbers, and captions are written in Leslie Stephen's autograph.
The album was purchased at auction on 6 December 1984 (Sotheby's, London, lot 289) and presented to the Mortimer Rare Book Room, Smith College, by Elizabeth Power Richardson and Phyllis Cooley Paige in memory of Mary Byers Smith. Twenty-three leaves were removed before the London sale and disbursed, including many photographs by Julia Margaret Cameron.
The material is divided into seven series following the order in which they were mounted by Leslie Stephen. The appendix contains a listing of the photographs in chronological order, a listing of the people pictured, and a short list of the places photographed.
Organization of the Collection
This collection is organized into seven series:
I. The Jackson family, 1875-1883
II. The Stephen family and friends, 1860-1890
III. The Jackson-Duckworth family, 1856-1871
IV. Leslie Stephen's early adulthood and marriage to Harriet Marian (Minny) Thackeray Stephen, with friend, 1860-1875
V. Leslie Stephen's marriage to Julia Duckworth Stephen and their young, 1879-1886
VI. Julia and Leslie Stephen, their children, and friends at Talland House, St. Ives, Cornwall, 1880-1894
VII. Julia and Leslie Stephens in Switzerland, 1889
Arrangement of the Collection
The material is divided into seven series following the order in which they were mounted by Leslie Stephen. The appendix contains a listing of the photographs in chronological order, a listing of the people pictured, and a short list of the places photographed.
Information on Use
Additional Formats
Images from this collection are also available in the online exhibition Leslie Stephen's Photograph Album.
History of the Collection
The album was purchased at auction on 6 December 1984 (Sotheby's, London, lot 289) and presented to the Mortimer Rare Book Room, Smith College, by Elizabeth Power Richardson and Phyllis Cooley Paige in memory of Mary Byers Smith. The Leslie Stephen Photograph Album is the physical property of the Mortimer Rare Book Room, Smith College.
Search Terms
Stephen, Leslie, Sir, 1832-1904--Pictorial works.; Stephen, Harriet Marian, 1840-1875. Pictorial works.; Stephen, Julia Duckworth, 1846-1895--Pictorial works.; Bell, Vanessa, 1879-1961--Pictorial works.; Woolf, Virginia, 1882-1941--Pictorial works.; Stephen, Adrian--Pictorial works.; Lowell, James Russell, 1819-1891--Pictorial works.; James, Henry, 1843-1916--Pictorial works.; Duckworth, Stella--Pictorial works.; Photography--Great Britian--19th century.; Cameron, Julia Margaret Pattle, 1815-1879.; Cameron, Henry Herschel Hay, 1852-1911.; Silvy, Camille-Léon-Louis, 1834-1910.; Loppé, Gabriel.; Rejlander, O. G. (Oscar Gustav), 1813-1875.
Additional Information
Separated Material
Twenty-three leaves were removed before the London sale and disbursed, including many photographs by Julia Margaret Cameron.
- Contents page of Leslie Stephen's Photograph Album c. 1895 (Box 1)
  Written in Leslie Stephen's autograph.
- Citations are to Elizabeth P. Richardson's A Bloomsbury Iconography (Winchester: St Paul's Bibliographies, 1989) (Box 1)
- Leaves 1-15 lacking.
- Series I. The Jackson family, 1875-1883, Leaves: 16, 17 & 24.
  This series pictures Julia Duckworth Stephen's parents Maria Pattle Jackson and Dr. John Jackson, and her two aunts Lady Somers and Louisa Pattle Bayley.
  - Drawing by G. F. Watts of Maria Pattle Jackson. n.d., Possibly Henry H. H. Cameron; Platinum print 23.6 x 18.9 cm. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): Mrs Jackson, from Watts's drawing
    Subject: Marie Pattle Jackson (1818-1892), mother of Julia Duckworth Stephen. (Cf. 38i)
    Richardson: Maria Jackson B1
  - Dr John Jackson, c.1883, Possibly Henry H. H. Cameron; Platinum print 23.8 x 18.2 cm. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): Dr Jackson (about 1883)
    Subject: John Jackson (1804-1887), physician, father of Julia Duckworth Stephen.
    Richardson: John Jackson A3
    Leaves 18-23 lacking.
  - Lady Somers, c. 1875, Anonymous; Albumen print 13.8 x 9.7 cm. (Box 1, Folder 24a)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): Lady Somers
    Subject: Virginia Pattle Somers-Cocks (1827-1910), aunt of Julia Duckworth Stephen.
  - Louisa Pattle Bayley, n.d., Oscar G. Rejlander; Albumen print 21.8 x 15.9 cm. (Box 1, Folder 24b)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): Mrs Bayley
    Subject: Louisa Pattle Bayley (1821-1873), aunt of Julia Duckworth Stephen.
- Series II. The Stephen family and friends, 1860-1890., Leaves: 25, 28, 29 & 30.
  This series pictures Leslie Stephen, his mother (Lady Jane Catherine Venn Stephen), his sister (Caroline Emelia Stephen), his brother (Sir James Fitzjames Stephen), his nephew (James Kenneth Stephen), and a family friend James Russell Lowell, an American writer and godfather of Virginia Woolf.
  - Leslie Stephen, late 1860s?, Julia Margaret Cameron; Platinum print 23.2 x 18.5 cm. (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): Leslie Stephen
    Subject: Leslie Stephen (1832-1904), author, editor. This print, which is cropped, may have been made by Henry H. H. Cameron.
    Richardson: Leslie Stephen A7
    Leaves 26-27 lacking.
  - Caroline Emelia Stephen, n.d., Anonymous; Albumen print 14.5 x 10.2 cm. (Box 1, Folder 28a)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): C. E. Stephen
    Subject: Caroline Emelia Stephen (1834-1909), sister of Leslie Stephen.
  - Sir James Fitzjames Stephen, n.d., Anonymous; Albumen print 15 x 10.3 cm. (Box 1, Folder 28b)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): James Fitzjames Stephen
    Subject: Sir James Fitzjames Stephen (1829-1894), brother of Leslie Stephen.
  - Jane Catherine Venn Stephen, n.d., Anonymous; Albumen print 20.3 x 14.4 cm. (Box 1, Folder 28c)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): Lady Stephen
    Subject: Jane Catherine Venn Stephen (1793-1875), mother of Leslie Stephen.
  - James Russell Lowell, n.d., Possibly Henry H. H. Cameron; Platinum print 22.2 x 17.5 cm. (Box 1, Folder 29)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): James Russell Lowell
    Subject: James Russell Lowell (1819-1891), American writer, godfather of Virginia Woolf.
  - James Kenneth Stephen, 1890, Possibly Henry H. H. Cameron; Platinum print 22.6 x 18.7 cm. (Box 1, Folder 30)
    Inscribed: done at the command of she who must be obeyed. / Jem. / Dec. 1890.
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): James Kenneth Stephen
    Subject: James Kenneth Stephen (1859-1892), poet, son of Sir James Fitzjames Stephen.
    Richardson: James Kenneth Stephen A5
- Series III. The Jackson-Duckworth family, 1856-1871., Leaves: 31, 32, 33 & 34.
  This series pictures Julia Duckworth Stephen, her first husband Herbert Duckworth, and their children George, Stella and Gerald. It also contains pictures of Saxonbury, the house of the Jackson family, and Orchard Leigh, the Duckworth family seat.
  - Julia Jackson, c. 1856, Anonymous; Albumen print 11.3 x 9.4 cm. (Box 1, Folder 31a)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): Julia (about 1856)
    Subject: Julia Duckworth Stephen (1846-1895), in a cape.
    Richardson: Julia Stephen A3
  - Drawing by G. F. Watts of Julia Jackson, n.d., Anonymous; Platinum print 20.7 x 15.6 cm. (Box 1, Folder 31b)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): Julia (about 1851) / from Watts's drawing
    Subject: Julia Duckworth Stephen (1846-1895).
    Richardson: Julia Stephen A1
  - Saxonbury, n.d., Anonymous; Albumen print 17.6 x 23.2 cm. (Box 1, Folder 32)
    Subject: Saxonbury, Frant, East Sussex, England, house of the Jackson family.
  - Julia and Herbert Duckworth, 1867, Possibly Oscar G. Rejlander; Albumen print 19.6 x 14.5 cm. (Box 1, Folder 33a)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): Julia and Herbert Duckworth
    Subject: Julia Duckworth Stephen (1846-1895) standing, profile right, behind Herbert Duckworth (1833-1870), seated, profile left. Julia Jackson married Herbert Duckworth in May 1867.
    (Cf. 33c and 34g)
  - Orchard Leigh, n.d., Anonymous; Albumen print 14.7 x 20 cm. (Box 1, Folder 33b)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): Orchard Leigh / (Herbert Duckworth with gun / on the left)
    Subject: Orchard Leigh (Duckworth family seat), near Frome, Somerset, England.
  - Julia Duckworth, 1867, Possibly Oscar G. Rejlander; Albumen print 19.6 x 14.5 cm. (Box 1, Folder 33c)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): Julia Duckworth
    Subject: Julia Duckworth Stephen (1846-1895), full length, standing, profile right.
    Richardson: Julia Stephen C1
  - Herbert Duckworth, n.d., Anonymous; Albumen print 9.3 x 5.8 cm. (Box 1, Folder 34a)
    Subject: Herbert Duckworth (1833-1870), in barrister's wig and gown.
  - Herbert Duckworth, n.d., Anonymous; Albumen print 9.3 x 5.9 cm. (Box 1, Folder 34b)
    Subject: Herbert Duckworth (1833-1870), standing, top hat on table.
  - Julia Duckworth, n.d., Anonymous; Albumen print 9.1 x 5.8 cm. (Box 1, Folder 34c)
    Subject: Julia Duckworth Stephen (1846-1895), head and shoulders.
  - Herbert Duckworth, n.d., Anonymous; Albumen print 8.5 x 5.5 cm. (Box 1, Folder 34d)
    Subject: Herbert Duckworth (1833-1870), seated reading.
    (Cf. 34h)
  - Julia Duckworth, n.d., Anonymous; Albumen print 8.6 x 6.0 cm. (Box 1, Folder 34e)
    Subject: Julia Duckworth Stephen (1846-1895), seated, profile left.
  - Julia Duckworth with George, c.1868, Anonymous; Albumen print 8.8 x 5.8 cm. (Box 1, Folder 34f)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): with George
    Subject: Julia Duckworth Stephen (1846-1895), profile right, holding baby George Duckworth (1868-1934).
  - Herbert Duckworth, n.d., Possibly Oscar G. Rejlander; Albumen print 17.8 x 13.6 cm. (Box 1, Folder 34g)
    Subject: Herbert Duckworth (1833-1870), seated with hands clasped.
    (Cf. 33a)
  - Herbert Duckworth, n.d., Anonymous; Albumen print 8.5 x 5.5 cm. (Box 1, Folder 34h)
    Subject: Herbert Duckworth (1833-1870), seated holding papers.
    (Cf. 34d)
  - Nurse with Gerald Duckworth, c.1871, Anonymous; Albumen print 9.5 x 5.7 cm. (Box 1, Folder 34i)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): with Gerald
    Subject: Woman (possibly Nurse Leyden) holding baby Gerald Duckworth (1870-1937), who is wearing a black mourning ribbon.
  - Julia Duckworth with Stella, c.1869, Anonymous; Albumen print 9.5 x 5.9 cm. (Box 1, Folder 34j)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): with Stella
    Subject: Julia Duckworth Stephen (1846-1895), seated, holding baby Stella Duckworth (1869-1897).
  - Julia Duckworth, early 1870s, Anonymous; Albumen print 9.6 x 6.1 cm. (Box 1, Folder 34k)
    Subject: Julia Duckworth Stephen (1846-1895) in mourning. Herbert Duckworth died in September 1870.
  - Julia Duckworth with Stella, early 1870s, Anonymous; Albumen print 9.6 x 6.1 cm. (Box 1, Folder 341)
    Subject: Julia Duckworth Stephen (1846-1895) in mourning, with Stella Duckworth (1869-1897), standing, holding a doll.
- Series IV. Leslie Stephen's early adulthood and marriage to Harriet Marian (Minny) Thackeray Stephen, with friend, 1860-1875., Leaf 35.
  This series pictures Leslie Stephen with his first wife Harriet Marian (Minny) Thackeray Stephen, their daughter, Laura Makepeace Stephen, and the Swiss alpine guide, Melchoir Anderegg.
  - Leslie Stephen, 1860, Camille Silvy; Albumen print 8.6 x 5.3 cm. (Box 1, Folder 35a)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): about 1860
    Caption (in an unknown autograph): by Camille Silvy
    Subject: Leslie Stephen (1832-1904), clean-shaven, leaning against a table.
    Richardson: Leslie Stephen A2
  - Leslie Stephen and Melchoir Anderegg, 1864, Anonymous; Albumen print 12.7 x 8.5 cm. (Box 1, Folder 35b)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): with Melchior Anderegg (1864)
    Subject: Leslie Stephen (1832-1904) at Meiringen, Switzerland, standing with his Alpine guide Melchoir Anderegg.
    (Cf. 39d)
    Richardson: Leslie Stephen A4
  - Leslie Stephen, 1862, Anonymous; Albumen print 9.0 x 5.3 cm. (Box 1, Folder 35c)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): 1862
    Subject: Leslie Stephen (1832-1904) full length, trimmed beard, holding an alpenstock.
  - Harriet and Leslie Stephen, 1867, Anonymous; Albumen print 9.3 x 5.9 cm. (arched top) (Box 1, Folder 35d)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): with Minny
    Subject: Harriet Marian Thackeray Stephen (1840-1875) and Leslie Stephen (1832-1904) standing outdoors, probably on their wedding trip. They were married 19 June 1867.
    Richardson: Harriet Marian Stephen B1 and Leslie Stephen A8
  - Leslie Stephen, c.1860, Anonymous; Albumen print 19.7 x 15.8 cm. (Box 1, Folder 35e)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): About 1860 (or earlier)
    Subject: Leslie Stephen (1832-1904) clean-shaven, seated.
    Richardson: Leslie Stephen A1
  - Laura Stephen, c. 1870, Anonymous; Albumen print 9.3 x 5.8 cm. (arched top) (Box 1, Folder 35f)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen autograph): Laura
    Subject: Head as a baby of Laura Makepeace Stephen (1870-1945).
  - Leslie Stephen with Troy, 1875, Anonymous; Albumen print 8.6 x 5.4 cm. (Box 1, Folder 35g)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): with Troy
    Subject: Leslie Stephen (1832-1904), seated, with his dog Troy.
    Richardson: Leslie Stephen A9
  - Leslie Stephen, 1864, Anonymous; Albumen print 9.4 x 5.8 cm. (arched top) (Box 1, Folder 35h)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): 1864
    Subject: Leslie Stephen (1832-1904) profile left, on which an 1870 engraving by Edward Whymper was based.
    Richardson: A6
- Series V. Leslie Stephen's marriage to Julia Duckworth Stephen and their young children, 1879-1886., Leaf: 36.
  This series depicts Leslie Stephen and his second wife, Julia Duckworth Stephen, and their four young children, Vanessa (later married Clive Bell), Thoby, Virginia (later married Leonard Woolf) and Adrian.
  - Julia Stephen, 1880s, Anonymous; Albumen print 8.3 x 5.7 cm. (Box 1, Folder 36a)
    Subject: Julia Duckworth Stephen (1846-1895) head and shoulders, three-quarter left, ruff, and locket.
  - Julia Stephen with Vanessa, 1879, Anonymous; Albumen print 9.4 x 6.0 cm. (Box 1, Folder 36b)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): with Vanessa (1879)
    Subject: Julia Duckworth Stephen (1846-1895) seated outdoors with baby Vanessa Bell (1879-1961).
  - Julia Stephen with Vanessa, 1879, Anonymous; Albumen print 9.8 x 6.0 cm. (Box 1, Folder 36c)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): with Vanessa
    Subject: Julia Duckworth Stephen (1846-1895), profile left, with baby Vanessa Bell (1879-1961) indoors.
  - Julia Stephen with Vanessa, 1879, Anonymous; Albumen print 8.0 x 6.0 cm. (Box 1, Folder 36d)
    Subject: Julia Duckworth Stephen (1846-1895), seated with baby Vanessa Bell (1879-1961) in her lap.
  - Vanessa Stephen, c.1881, Anonymous; Albumen print 14.2 x 10.0 cm. (Box 1, Folder 36e)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): Vanessa
    Subject: Vanessa Bell (1879-1961), aged about two.
  - Julia Stephen with Virginia, 1884, Henry H. H. Cameron; Platinum print 20.0 x 14.0 cm. (Box 1, Folder 36f)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): with Virginia
    Subject: Julia Duckworth Stephen (1846-1895) with Virginia Woolf (1882-1941) on her lap.
    Richardson: Julia Stephen D2 and Virginia Woolf A1
  - Thoby Stephen, c.1882, Anonymous; Albumen print 13.8 x 9.6 cm. (Box 1, Folder 36g)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): Julian Thoby
    Subject: Head of Thoby Stephen (1880-1906), aged about two. Thoby's full name was Julian Thoby Stephen.
  - Julia Stephen with Adrian, c.1886, Anonymous; Albumen print 12.7 x 7.8 cm. (arched top) (Box 1, Folder 36h)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): with Adrian
    Subject: Julia Duckworth Stephen (1846-1895) with Adrian Stephen (1883-1948), aged about two or three, in her lap.
  - Thoby Stephen, early 1880s, Lock & Whitfield; Albumen print 14.1 x 9.9 cm. (Box 1, Folder 36i)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): Thoby
    Subject: Thoby Stephen (1880-1906), aged about four or five, seated on a balustrade with a shrimping net.
  - Julia Stephen with Vanessa, early 1880s, Anonymous; Albumen print 14.1 x 9.9 cm. (Box 1, Folder 36j)
    Subject: Julia Duckworth Stephen (1846-1895) with Vanessa Bell (1879-1961), aged about four, in her lap.
- Series VI. Julia and Leslie Stephen, their children, and friends at Talland House, St. Ives, Cornwall, 1880-1894., Leaves: 37-38.
  This series pictures Julia and Leslie Stephen with their children George, Stella and Gerald (all Duckworth) and Vanessa, Thoby, Virginia and Adrian (all Stephen) with their family dog Shag at Talland house. Also present are friends Horatio Brown and Henry James.
  Note: Leaf 37- This leaf, labeled 'In the holidays' on the contents page, includes photographs of Julia and Leslie Stephen and their children at Talland House, St Ives, Cornwall, England, where they spent their summer holidays from 1892 through 1894. The leaf was donated to the Mortimer Rare Book Room, Smith College, by Quentin and Anne Olivier Bell. It had been detached from the album.
  - Stephen-Duckworth Wimbledon Group, 1894, Anonymous; Albumen print 7.8 x 10.4 cm. (Box 1, Folder 37a)
    Caption below (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): At Alenhoe, Wimbledon, 1894
    Caption on left: J.P.S. / A.L.S.
    Caption on right: L.S.
    Caption above: G.de l'E Ginia Thoby Vanessa George
    Subject: A family photograph of Gerald Duckworth, Virginia Woolf, Thoby Stephen, Vanessa Bell, and George Duckworth (back row); Adrian Stephen, Julia Duckworth Stephen, and Leslie Stephen (front row).
    Richardson: Stephen-Duckworth Wimbledon Group
  - St Ives, c.1882-1894, Anonymous; Silver print 7.4 x 10.2 cm. (Box 1, Folder 37b)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): St Ives from Stella's window
    Subject: View of St Ives, Cornwall, England.
  - Talland House, c.1882-1994, Anonymous; Silver print 10.3 x 14.7 cm. (Box 1, Folder 37c)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): Talland House
    Subject: Front view of Talland House, St Ives, Cornwall, England.
    Richardson: Talland House A1
  - Julia Stephen with Virginia and Adrian, 1890s, Anonymous; Silver print 7 x 7 cm. (Box 1, Folder 37d)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): At drawing room window. / Julia with A.V.S. and A.L.S.